Dr Andrew Benito

↑ andrewbenito 💆 _abenito 🖂 abenito.work@gmail.com | *Updated:* December 10, 2021

Personal

Nationality: British and Irish citizen. Born: Burnley, U.K.

www: andrewbenito.github/AlphaBetEcon

Profile

Chief European Economist at Eisler Capital. Previously, Managing Director at Goldman Sachs (8 years) and Research Manager at Bank of England (12 years, including secondments to the IMF and Banco de Espana). My work has been cited extensively by policy-makers and the media and been published in academic journals. I hold a PhD in Economics from the University of Warwick. I am also a Research Fellow at IZA, Institute of Labor Economics, Bonn.

Employment	
Chief European Economist Eisler Capital	2019 -
Managing Director, Chief UK Economist and Senior European Economist Goldman Sachs, Global Macro Research	2011 - 2019
Research Manager Bank of England, Monetary Analysis	2008 - 11
Visiting Scholar International Monetary Fund, Research Department (seconded from Bank of England)	2006 -08
Senior Economist Bank of England, Monetary Analysis	2003 - 06
Senior Economist Banco de Espana, Research Department (seconded from Bank of England)	2002 - 03
Economist Bank of England, Financial Stability	1999 - 2002
Leader, Modelling Team Oxford Economic Research Associates	1997 - 99
Education	
Ph.D. Economics University of Warwick	1994 - 97
Thesis: Wage Premia in the British Labour Market	
M.Sc. Economics University of Warwick	1993 - 94
B.Sc. Economics Cardiff University	1990 - 93

1 1/3

Journal Publications

Benito, A and Saleheen, J (2013), 'Labour supply as a buffer: Evidence from UK households', *Economica* 80, 698-720

Benito, A and Mumtaz, H (2009), 'Excess sensitivity, liquidity constraints and the collateral role of housing', *Macroeconomic Dynamics*, 13, 305-326

Benito, A (2009), 'Who withdraws housing equity and why?', Economica, 76, 51-70

Benito, A and Hernando, I (2008), 'Labour demand, flexible contracts and financial factors', *Oxford Bulletin of Economics and Statistics*, 70, 283-301

Benito, A and Hernando, I (2007), 'Financial pressure and firm behaviour: Evidence from Spanish panel data', *Bulletin of Economic Research*, 59, 283-311

Benito, A and Young, G (2007), 'Financial pressure and balance sheet adjustment by firms', Oxford Bulletin of Economics and Statistics, 69, 581-602.

Benito, A (2007), 'The down-payment constraint and UK housing market: Does the theory fit the facts?', *Journal of Housing Economics*, 15, 1-20

Benito, A (2006), 'Does job insecurity affect household consumption?', Oxford Economic Papers, 56, 157-81

Benito, A (2005), 'Financial pressure, monetary policy effects and inventories: Firm-level evidence from a market-based and a bank-based financial system', *Economica*, 72, 201-224

Benito, A and Young, G (2003), 'Hard Times or Great Expectations? Dividend omissions and dividend cuts by UK firms', Oxford Bulletin of Economics and Statistics, 65, 531-57

Benito, A (2000), 'Inter-industry wage differentials in Great Britain', Oxford Bulletin of Economics and Statistics, 62, 727-746

Institutional Publications

Benito, A. and Young, G. (2021), 'The UK productivity shortfall in an era of rising labour supply', *IZA Discussion Paper* 14620

Benito, A. (2018), 'Missing wage growth and ECB policy', European Views, Goldman Sachs Research

Benito, A. et al. (2017), 'Drivers of UK asset prices - Since Brexit, politics matters more than economics', *European Economics Analyst*. Goldman Sachs Research

Benito, A. (2017), 'How does monetary policy affect labor demand and labor productivity?', *IZA World of Labor*.

Benito, A. and Saleheen, J. (2012), 'Labour supply as a buffer: Evidence from UK households', *IZA Discussion Paper 6506* (Also, *Bank of England Working Paper No.426*).

Benito, A. and Bunn, P. (2011), 'Understanding labour force participation in the UK', Bank of England Quarterly Bulletin

Benito, A. et al (2010), 'The effect of the financial crisis on supply', Bank of England Quarterly Bulletin

2

2/3

Benito, A., et al (2007), The role of household debt and balance sheets in the monetary transmission mechanism', Bank of England Quarterly Bulletin

Benito, A. (2007), 'What risks do housing markets pose for global growth?', IMF World Economic Outlook

Benito, A. (2007), 'Housing market slowdowns', IMF World Economic Outlook

Benito, A., et al (2006), 'House prices and consumer spending', Bank of England Quarterly Bulletin

Benito, A. and Wood, R.(2005), 'How important is housing market activity for durables spending?', Bank of England Quarterly Bulletin

Benito, A. and Power, J. (2004), 'Housing equity and consumption: insights from the Survey of English Housing', *Bank of England Quarterly Bulletin*, Autumn, 302-309.

Benito, A. and Hernando, I. (2004), 'Demanda de trabajo, contratos temporales y factores financieros', Banco de Espana Boletin Economico pp 71-74

Benito, A., et al (2001), 'Analysing corporate and household sector balance sheets', Bank of England Financial Stability Review

Benito, A. and Vlieghe, G. (2000), 'Stylised facts on UK corporate financial health: Evidence from micro-data', Bank of England Financial Stability Review.

Awards

• IZA Research Fellow	2011-
Special Session Award, Money Macro Finance Conf., Cambridge	2003
Human Capital and Mobility Fellowship, European Union	1995-97
 University Graduate Award}, University of Warwick 	1993-94
Sir Julian Hodge Award	1993
 Vauxhall Motors Award for Academic Excellence 	1993

Seminars

Banco de Espana, Bank of England, Banque de France, European Central Bank, European Economic Association, European University Institute, Goldman Sachs (London), Harvard University, International Monetary Fund, London School of Economics, Royal Economic Society Annual Conference, Society of Professional Economists, University of Cambridge, Universidad Carlos III Madrid, University of Oxford, University of Warwick.

3

3/3